Sami Mabrouk

Software Engineer | San Diego, CA (Remote) | 858.733.1242 | samimabrouk10@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/mabrouk10/ | https://mabrouk10.github.io/portfolio/ | github.com/mabrouk10

Summary

Software Engineer with strong analytical and logical skills dedicated to building and optimizing creative web applications that provide intuitive user experiences. Strong skills developed in critical thinking, leadership, communication and teamwork from previous work experiences as a Research Associate, Full Stack Developer Intern, Software QA Analyst and Software Engineer Intern.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages:

- Java
- Python
- Javascript
- HTML/CSS
- Ruby

Frameworks:

- React
- Ruby on Rails

Version Control:

Git

Testing:

- Jest
- Rspec

Databases:

- PostgreSQL
- Active Record

Other related skills:

- Data Structures & Algorithms
- Discrete Mathematics/Statistics
- Linux/Windows/Bash Scripting
- JIRA/Confluence

Experience

Family Proud | Software Engineer Intern | San Diego CA

Jan. 2021 - Present

- Software Engineering Intern for a healthcare tech startup developing web and mobile based (Android/iOS) applications ensuring easy processing of care and resources amongst patients and families in need.
- Established experience in responsive UI development and experience in ReactJS, Redux, React native, Material UI and Firebase

LEARN Academy | Software Engineer in Training | San Diego CA

Nov. 2020 - Jan. 2021

- 12 week full time coding bootcamp specializing in JavaScript, React, Ruby, Rails, and PostgreSQL
- Contributed to application development through extensive pair and mob programming
- Completed 480+ hours of direct coding experience
- Obtained proficiency in test-driven development utilizing Rspec and Jest

snaploT | Software QA Analyst | San Diego CA

Aug. 2020 - Nov. 2020

- Planned and coordinated testing activities using JIRA and Confluence
- Designed traceability matrices, test plans and test scripts for software requirements
- Managed and distributed assets and documentation from creative team to the engineering team
- Conducted integration, version, regression, user acceptance testing

Orlando Inc | Full Stack Developer Intern | San Diego CA

Sep. 2020 - Oct. 2020

- Learning MEAN development stack (MongoDB, Express.js, Angular, Node.js) stack to build applications for aviation schools
- Collaborating with UI/UX designers, full stack developers/engineers and CEO to create design decisions, reiterate
 group objectives and set future milestones.

Education

University of California, San Diego

Bachelor of Science: General Biology (Completed)

Minor: Computer Science (In Progress)

June 2019